E S

DATA SCIENTIST

(415) 999-9096

alessio.gabriela@mail.com

In LinkedIn.com/in/gabrielaalessio

Github.com/galessiorob

San Francisco, CA

EDUCATION

MBA, Concentration in Analytics

University of San Francisco 2014 — 2016

BS, Chemical Engineering

Universidad Iberoamericana 2006 - 2010

Inference and ML Course

MIT 2020

Marketing Certificate

Stanford University 2016

Financial Analytics Certificate

UC Berkeley 2014

SKILLS

Python, SQL, R, Hive, Presto, Airflow Looker, Tableau and Plotly Deck design and data visualization Data cleansing, modeling and mining Machine Learning Stakeholder and team management **Business Strategy**

AWARDS

Beta Gamma Sigma, Honors 2016 Prospanica Scholar 2014-2016

LANGUAGES

English (fluent) Spanish (fluent) French (conversational)

SUMMARY

I am Data Scientist with vast experience at collecting, analyzing, and interpreting large datasets, developing new forecasting models, and performing data management tasks. I am obsessed with understanding users through data and effectively communicating and translating complex concepts and data sets into effective visuals and insights, to solve pain points and delight through features.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DATA SCIENTIST

GitHub | Sep 2017 — to date

- Built the company's A/B testing framework, process and reporting from the ground up, currently used across multiple teams for the majority of new feature releases and larger Marketing efforts.
- Lead the engineering of the canonical model for conversion and financial reporting, which I used afterwards to do scenario analysis for pricing changes.
- Translated multiple technical analysis into data packs for the executive teams, the latest one leading to a major change in pricing and packaging
- Designed the "voice" and brand guidelines for the Data Science team and all the content produced for internal and external consumption.

PRODUCT MARKETING ANALYST

Salesforce | Feb 2017 — Sep 2017

- Re-designed the OKR measurement strategy for multiple internal and external stakeholders.
- ETLed sources to produce insight and foresight into campaign performance, to translate findings into actions to ensure marketing success for partners.
- Data mining and interpreting for the AppExchange platform, influencing internal Marketing and Product strategies.

PRODUCT MARKETING ANALYST

Gap Inc | Jun 2016 — Feb 2017

- Partnered with Marketing teams for each brand to develop targeted and segmented communications campaigns based on personalization algorithms, resulting in a 35% engagement/action increase.
- Championed the adoption of Social Analytics as key input in the design process, by building a campaign case with Old Navy helping the team understand historical hits and misses; results include the expansion of the active wear line which is now one of the fastest growing segments.

CREDIT ANALYST

INVEX Group | Jan 2011 — Jan 2013

• Designed model to determine product pricing, budget, cost and ROI on client acquisition for Mexico's metropolitan zones.